<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Dr Matthew Ellis</title>
    <link>https://mattoaellis.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://mattoaellis.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://mattoaellis.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://mattoaellis.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent Articles</title>
      <link>https://mattoaellis.github.io/post/recent-articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattoaellis.github.io/post/recent-articles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to the pandemic a couple of my projects ended up being a little later than planned so in the last few months
we have had a couple more articles published on our neuromorphic and reservoir computing work. The first paper was published
in Advanced Functional Materials on the emergent dynamics in a set of magnetic rings that we found could be used for reservoir computing.
The experimental work was performed by researchers in the Department of Materials Science who manufactured and measured the
properties of a grid of interconnected rings. The domain walls in these rings become pinned at the interfaces and can interact
causing the emergent dynamics. As a reservoir it has a range of important properties (fading memory, non-linearity, etc) and we
found excellent performance on a speech recognition task. The paper is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202008389&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next paper was an invited paper in Applied Physics Letters for a special topic on Mesoscopic Magnetic Systems in which we introduced
a novel reservoir based on thermally activated magnetic dots. While it might appear that the stochastic behaviour of
these dots do not have much to offer, we found by applying a voltage controlled anisotropy we can tune the relaxation
rates from one orientiation to another. Importantly this system is low energy so could find use in edge-computing
systems where energy is limited. You can find the full article &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0048911&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most recently we have puclished our work on a non-linear domain wall oscillator as a physical reservoir. This was again
in collaboration with Materials Science and we built a 1D model of the domain wall motion when it is pinned between
two anti-notches. The pinning potential exhibits chaotic behaviour for fields upto 1.2 KA/m and a non-linear response beyond
this. From this we could train it using the reservoir computing approach and found good performance on a set of tasks. You can read more &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-021-94975-y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming Papers</title>
      <link>https://mattoaellis.github.io/post/upcoming-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 09:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattoaellis.github.io/post/upcoming-papers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was nice early Christmas present that we heard that two of our recent submissions had been accepted.
The first was invited article in Frontiers in Applied Mathematics and Statistics where we have been looking
at hierarchical (or deep) echo state networks and how we can tune them to exhibit multiple timescales.
The abstract is available on the Frontiers &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/fams.2020.616658/abstract&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;webpage&lt;/a&gt; and the full article should be available soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second was a collaboration with the University of York that has been ongoing since my PhD. This is developing a combined model of spin and moelcular dynamics which are
simulated concurrently. A few models of spin-lattice dynamics have been proposed already but here we present some novel results of the Gilbert damping caused by the coupling
of the spin system to lattice. This is a very interesting topic and we will be using our model to explore spin-lattice dynamics in the future. Whilst the article is not yet out
at Physical Review B, the pre-print can be found on Arxiv &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2010.00642&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year</title>
      <link>https://mattoaellis.github.io/post/new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 16:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mattoaellis.github.io/post/new-year/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy new year everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moving into 2021 I have started a small refresh of this website. I have updated the publications and
added a new post about our upcoming papers. 2020 was a strange year of lockdowns and lots of working
from home, 2021 is looking similar so far but fingers crossed for a productive and interesting year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
